Roman Gusev Senior Software Engineer

Status: B.Sc. Software Engineering, M.Sc. Education, Web Development Engineer **Fields:** Software Engineering, Frontend Development, Backend Development, Scrum

Techs: JavaScript, TypeScript, Flow, React, Next.js, MongoDB, Python

Amsterdam, the Netherlands rgusev2@gmail.com GitHub: 102

Summary

Expert software engineer with specialization in web development. A lot of experience working with remote distributed teams in the agile environment. Special interests: working with the code as data (AST manipulations, linters, codemods) and breaking the obstacles between product and development parts of the team.

Experience

Lead Software Engineer — EPAM Systems

2020-

- · Leading the team of 15-20 JavaScript developers
- · Technologies used: Node.js, React, GraphQL, Next.js

Senior Developer — SSP Software

2020-2020

- · Working on the large-scale web development projects
- · Technologies used: TypeScript, React, Redux

Code Reviewer — TripleTen

2020-2020

- · Reviewing students' code in JavaScript, Express, and MongoDB
- · Part-time contracting job

Software Engineer — Hello World! Technologies

2015-2019

- · Working on a lot of outsourcing projects for clients around the world
- · Technologies used: JavaScript, Flow, React, Express.js, MongoDB, PHP, Python

Education

Master of Science in Education — Omsk State Pedagogical University

2016-2018

- · Master's Thesis: Design of CLIL courses for Computer Science students
- · Classes specialized in English and German language education and intercultural communication

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering — Omsk State University

2012-2016

- · Bachelor's Thesis: Implementation of web API wrapper for proprietary integrated library system
- Mastered computer science and software engineering courses

Projects

Retail Network - NDA

2021-

- Migrating large-scale e-shop solution from the legacy Hybris frontend to the modern Next.js application. Performing a role of Guild Lead, Scrum Master and Team Lead. Interviewing developers, improving the developer expereince, quality gates, and facilitating a lot of meetings.
- · Technologies: JavaScript, Node.js, Next.js, GraphQL

Technical Interviewing — EPAM Systems

2021-

- · Technical interviewing of JavaScript engineers of various levels evaluating the skills and knowledge
- · Results: over 50 technical interviews, multiple hires

Clinical Trial Management System — NDA

2020-2021

- Migrating large-scale CTMS from legacy VBScript and Perl codebase to the modern JavaScript technologies. The main problem was the codebase that was only meant to run in the old IE versions. In order to complete the investigation step and help on the implementation step, scripts for code analysis and JIRA automation were created.
- · Technologies: VBScript, JavaScript, Node.is, Perl

- · Working in a scrum-like environment on a frontend part of the huge website with the micro-frontend architecture. Main responsibilities: new features implementation, migration from the AEM to React-based apps, maintaining JavaScript infrastructure
- · Technologies: TypeScript, React, Redux, Jenkins, AWS, Webpack

Review Platform for Blockchain-related projects — NDA

2017-2019

- Feature-rich SPA with a lot of content. I've started to build the project from scratch with raising the team size from 2 engineers to more than 10. My participation: all sides of the project, including backend and frontend development, deployment, blockchain integration, hot-fixing security problems, and building the proper way of communication between design, product, and development teams
- · Technologies: React, Redux, Express, Blockchain, Ethereum, Bitcoin, Azure Web Apps, Azure Functions

Interactive Educational Website for Children — NDA

2016-2017

- An educational single page web application for children in their early childhood. The main features are games, lessons, and songs. Thus the project included a lot of rich media content to work with including video, audio, and canvas.
- · Technologies: React, Redux, JSS, Webpack, Recompose, Gitlab CI

Programming Challenges Website — Kattis

2015-2016

- · Maintenance for the whole website infrastructure, from the frontend written in PHP and jQuery to the PHP backend and Python scripts used to manage deployments, migrations, and other operations
- · Technologies: PHP, Python, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap